Let's look at the PIMBock Guide.
Processes and integration management.
So we have our initiating
process group where we get
our project or phase
authorized to begin started.
We'll develop the project charter in that
process.
Remember, we're in
the integration knowledge
area going across that
row in your process map.
Planning.
Once we move out of initiating,
we'll move in two weeks.
planning.
So based on all the high level information
we have in our project charter,
we will then develop the project
management plan, figure out what we're
setting out to accomplish,
how we will do our processes,
how we'll take our project
from beginning to end.
So we'll figure out our plan
and then we'll go through the
other planning processes
below to figure out baselines.
then we'll move into executing.
So the focus is integration,
these processes, but
I'm giving you a little
background at the same time.
So once we're done planning, we've
developed our project management plan.
Think of it as a puzzle.
We'll move into executing to do the work
of the project according to the plan.
And what do we, the PM, what do we do?
We direct and manage the project work.
We have our plan, what's been authorized,
for our project the scope schedule and
costs now we will manage the work and our
team members as well as manage project
knowledge we'll be documenting as soon as
we're done planning we move into executing
and monitoring and controlling we do this
as soon as we're baseline we start doing
the work according to
the plan that's in executing
and move into of
monitoring and controlling.
We, remember, we're at the top overseeing
our entire project.
We will monitor and control the project
work and perform integrated change control.
We will get into all these processes and a
lot of detail in a minute.
All right, by the time
we're done with all the
work, we'll close, it
might just be a phase.
We'll close the project or phase.
If you have a phase project like
construction, for example.
Usually there's a design phase.
Once all the designs, blueprints and
everything's done, they'll be approved.
So closing, you'll get to an exit gate
where, okay, our key stakeholders decide
they don't want to move forward or they
do.
So we'll have our deliverables.
We'll close the project or phase and then
repeat in the next phase.